<document>
  <page>
    <block>CONFIDENTIALITY AGREEMENT</block>
    <block>DATED __________________ of ________________________ 20____</block>
    <block></block>
    <block>BETWEEN</block>
    <block><data>organisation.name</data> at <data>organisation.location</data> ("the Organisation")</block>
    <block>AND</block>
    <block if="contractor.type = person"><data>contractor.person.name</data> of <data>contractor.person.location</data>, <data>contractor.person.occupation</data> ("the Contractor")</block>
    <block if="contractor.type = company"><data>contractor.company.name</data> of <data>contractor.company.location</data> ("the Contractor")</block>
    <block></block>
    <block>BACKGROUND</block>
    <list>
      <list-item>The Organisation <data>organisation.description</data> ("the Business").</list-item>
      <list-item>The Contractor needs access to the Confidential Information <data>disclosure_reason</data> ("Purpose").</list-item>
      <list-item>The Organisation agrees to make the Confidential Information available to the Contractor in accordance with the terms and conditions set out in this agreement.</list-item>
    </list>
    <block></block>
    <block>OPERATIVE CLAUSES</block>
    <list start="continue">
      <list-item>
        DEFINITIONS AND INTERPRETATION
        <list>
          <list-item>
            In this agreement:
            <list>
              <list-item>"Business" is defined at 1.</list-item>
              <list-item>
                "Confidential Information" means information disclosed and shared, and discussions between the parties, in relation to <data>organisation.name</data>'s:
                <list>
                  <list-item>Business, operations or strategies;</list-item>
                  <list-item>Intellectual or other property; or</list-item>
                  <list-item>Actual or prospective customers, suppliers or competitors.</list-item>
                </list>
                The information must be one of the following:
                <list start="continue">
                  <list-item>Confidential in fact;</list-item>
                  <list-item>Reasonably regarded by <data if="contractor.type = person">contractor.person.name</data><data if="contractor.type = company">contractor.company.name</data> as confidential; or</list-item>
                  <list-item>Information that a written notice from <data>organisation.name</data> to <data if="contractor.type = person">contractor.person.name</data><data if="contractor.type = company">contractor.company.name</data> states is confidential.</list-item>
                </list>
              </list-item>
            </list>
          </list-item>
          <list-item>
            Interpretation:
            <list>
              <list-item>Headings where used are included for convenience only and shall have no effect upon the interpretation of this agreement; and</list-item>
              <list-item>The singular shall incorporate the plural and vice versa, references to one gender shall include all genders, and references to persons shall include bodies corporate.</list-item>
            </list>
          </list-item>
        </list>
      </list-item>
      <list-item>
        CONTRACTOR’S OBLIGATIONS
        <list>
          <list-item>
            The Contractor will keep the Confidential Information confidential at all times in the future, including after the termination of this agreement, except where:
            <list>
              <list-item>the information was already known to the Contractor before being disclosed by the Organisation under this or any other confidentiality agreement between the parties; or</list-item>
              <list-item>the information comes into the public domain other than by way of breach of this agreement; or</list-item>
              <list-item>the information is required by law to be disclosed by the Contractor. In such an event, the Contractor will only disclose the information to the party to whom it is required by law to make such disclosure.</list-item>
            </list>
          </list-item>
          <list-item>The Contractor will only use the Confidential Information for the Purpose.</list-item>
          <list-item>The Contractor will only disclose the information to such of its employees <inline if="disclosure_access = true">or <data>disclosure_access.details.persons</data></inline> as required to fulfil its obligations under this agreement, and on the basis that such people agree to abide by the terms and conditions of this agreement as if they were parties to the agreement.</list-item>
          <list-item>The Contractor will make such disclosure on the basis that if the employee <inline if="disclosure_access = true">or <data>disclosure_access.details.persons</data></inline> discloses the information in an unauthorised manner, the Contractor will be liable to the Organisation as if the Contractor had itself made such disclosure.</list-item>
          <list-item>The Contractor will return or destroy all copies of the Confidential Information in its possession or the possession of its employees <inline if="disclosure_access = true">or <data>disclosure_access.details.persons</data></inline> upon any termination of this agreement.</list-item>
          <list-item>At the request of the Organisation, the Contractor will return or destroy all copies of the Confidential Information in its possession or the possession of its employees<inline if="disclosure_access = true">or <data>disclosure_access.details.persons</data></inline>.</list-item>
          <list-item>The Contractor may not assign its rights and obligations in terms of this agreement without the prior written permission of the Organisation.</list-item>
        </list>
      </list-item>
      <list-item>
        <block>INDEMNITY</block>
        The Contractor indemnifies the Organisation against any loss, cost, expense, demand or liability arising out of any unauthorised disclosure of the Confidential Information or any other breach of this agreement by the Contractor.
      </list-item>
      <list-item>
        <block>AMENDMENTS AND/OR VARIATIONS</block>
        This agreement may be amended or varied by written agreement between the parties.
      </list-item>
      <list-item>
        <block>COUNTERPARTS</block>
        This agreement may be executed in one or more counterpart copies which, when read together, will constitute one and the same instrument.  Any facsimile copy or scanned email copy of this agreement (including any facsimile copy or scanned email copy of any document evidencing the execution of this agreement by either party) may be relied upon by the other party as though it were an original copy.
      </list-item>
      <list-item>
        <block>GOVERNING LAW</block>
        This Agreement will be subject to and interpreted in accordance with the laws of New Zealand and will be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the Courts of New Zealand.
      </list-item>
    </list>
    <block></block>
    <block>Signed for and on behalf of <data>organisation.name</data></block>
    <block></block>
    <block></block>
    <block>Name of representative:</block>
    <block></block>
    <block>Date:</block>
    <block></block>
    <block if="contractor.type = person">Signed by <data>contractor.person.name</data></block>
    <block if="contractor.type = company">Signed for and on behalf of <data>contractor.company.name</data></block>
    <block></block>
    <block></block>
    <block if="contractor.type = person"><data>contractor.person.name</data></block>
    <block if="contractor.type = company">Name of representative:</block>
    <block></block>
    <block>Date:</block>
    <signature if="contractor.type = person" signer="contractor.person.name"></signature>
    <signature if="contractor.type = company" signer="contractor.company.representative" representing="contractor.company.name"></signature>
  </page>
</document>